Tufts Programs Abroad Records UA030
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Programs Abroad Records
1954 -- 2018
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Office of Programs Abroad
University of Chile
Zhejiang University
University of Ghana (Legon)
University of Hong Kong
Kanazawa University
UA030
4.54 Linear Feet 11 boxes
1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object containing 4 files.
37.75 Megabytes
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by Tufts Programs Abroad, 2007-2018.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in two series: Tufts Programs Abroad and Annual reports and unprocessed accessions.
Biographical / Historical
The Tufts Overseas Program was formed in 1977 following a Committee Studying Tufts Overseas Programs recommendation after reviewing a number of Tufts programs abroad. At the time, there had been Tufts-programs going to Italy, Germany, Paris, West Africa, and London since 1961. These programs were originally organized and led by departments. The Committee Studying Tufts Overseas Programs recommended an administrative office to oversee these Tufts-in-X programs.
The name was changed in 1978 to Tufts Programs Abroad. It was administered by the Academic Dean's office. The first programs offered to Tufts undergraduate students were to England, France, and Germany. There was an additional program offered to Germany for Tufts graduate students.
In 1984, Tufts Programs Abroad were administered by the Office of Undergraduate Studies. There were programs available in England, France, Spain, U.S.S.R. and Germany for undergraduates and a graduate program in Germany.
In 2002, the name changed again to Office of Programs Abroad. There were Tufts Programs to Chile, China, Ghana, Hong Kong, Japan, London, Madrid, Oxford, Paris, and Tuebingen. Students were also allowed to go abroad through non-Tufts programs. Office of Programs Abroad facilitates undergraduate and graduate students plans to study abroad. They provide resources about the abroad experience, coordinate Tufts-planned programs, hold orientation meetings for exiting and returning to the United States, and oversee logistical problems of studying abroad.
Custodial History
All material accessioned prior to 1997 was originally arranged by subject, no attempt was made to recreate original order, although material relating to administering the collection was removed to the documentation files of the collection in the archives.
Most of the news clippings, photographs, press releases, and correspondence have been separated from the subject files. These types of materials are present however, throughout the subject files as well.
Related Materials
UA092, Tufts University European Center records, DCA
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials from the Tufts Study abroad programs. These materials include brochures, news clippings, correspondence, photographs, press releases, program guides, financial materials, annual reports, and other reports and statistics.
University history; Teaching and learning; Curriculum and Instruction
- Tufts Programs Abroad, 1954 -- 2010; UA030.001; 6.15 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes brochures, newsclippings, photographs, press releases, and correspondence in reference to the office of Tufts Programs Abroad and Tufts study abroad programs from the office's inception.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged as found.
  Conditions Governing Access
  20 years from date of creation. Open for research.
  - Tufts Summer Program in Belgium, 1989; UA030.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Open for research.
  - Tufts Summer Program in France, 1990 -- 1999; UA030.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad, 1989 -- 1993; UA030.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad, 1993 -- 1997; UA030.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Guidelines for Study Abroad, 1988 -- 1992; UA030.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Guidelines for Study Abroad, 1992 -- 1996; UA030.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Study Abroad Summer Programs in the French Alps, 2001; UA030.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Guidelines for Study Abroad, 2000 -- 2002; UA030.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Programs in the French Alps -- Talloires, 2005; UA030.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Programs in the French Alps -- Talloires, 2002; UA030.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Programs in the French Alps -- Talloires, 2003; UA030.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Programs in the French Alps Talloires, 2007, UA030.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - General, 1965 -- 1993; UA030.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Africa (Crossroads), 1962 -- 1963; UA030.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Barcelona, 1979 -- 1981; UA030.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Education in England, 1973 -- 1978; UA030.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Italy: Tufts-Brown-Wesleyan, 1969; UA030.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Italy--Cumae, general, 1960 -- 1961; UA030.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Italy--Cumae, 1960 -- 1961; UA030.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Italy--Cumae, 1962 -- 1963; UA030.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Italy--Cumae, 1963 -- 1964; UA030.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Italy--Cumae, 1964 -- 1965; UA030.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Tufts European Center (Talloires), 1979 -- 1981; UA030.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Tufts European Center (Talloires), photos and plans, 1979 -- 1980; UA030.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Italy, 1965 -- 1966; UA030.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Italy, 1966 -- 1967; UA030.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Italy, 1967 -- 1968; UA030.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Suspension of program in Italy, 1967 -- 1968; UA030.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Faculty/Staff information, 1967; UA030.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Italy, housing contracts, 1959 -- 1963; UA030.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Italy, housing contracts, leases, 1965 -- 1968; UA030.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Italy, housing, Pignatelli Museum, 1954 -- 1963; UA030.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Italy, inventories, 1965; UA030.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Italy: information for students, 1965 -- 1966; UA030.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Italy, legal file, 1967 -- 1969; UA030.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Italy, statistics, 1966 -- 1967; UA030.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Italy, lists, 1965 -- 1968; UA030.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Italy, summer school, 1965 -- 1966; UA030.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Tufts in London, general, 1967 -- 1983; UA030.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Tufts in London, budget, 1967 -- 1968; UA030.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - London, correspondence, 1966 -- 1980; UA030.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - London, faculty correspondence, 1966 -- 1977; UA030.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - London, Forsyth correspondence, 1966 -- 1971; UA030.001.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - London, Statt--Manos cases, 1981 -- 1984; UA030.001.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - Students, 1967 -- 1979; UA030.001.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - Paris, general, 1965 -- 1979; UA030.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Paris, correspondence, (Fabre), 1965 -- 1980; UA030.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, program finances, 1975 -- 1977; UA030.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Paris, information for students, 1965 -- 1968; UA030.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Paris, students, 1967 -- 1980; UA030.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Tubingen, correspondence (Myrvaagnes), 1965 -- 1966; UA030.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Tubingen, students, 1965 -- 1972; UA030.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Tubingen, general, 1964 -- 1979; UA030.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Tufts in Tubingen, Hallowell visit, 1972; UA030.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, general, 1962 -- 1977; UA030.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, Education in England, 1973 -- 1977; UA030.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, Hull, 1977; UA030.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, Italy, 1960; UA030.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, London, 1966 -- 1977; UA030.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, London (Drama), 1977; UA030.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee Tubingen, 1975 -- 1977; UA030.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, West Africa, 1969 -- 1977; UA030.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, Paris, 1964 -- 1977; UA030.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee, Paris: evaluations, 1977; UA030.001.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee on Programs Abroad, Evaluation Committee, 1976 -- 1977; UA030.001.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - Tufts Programs Abroad Committee report, 1977; UA030.001.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - "In Appreciation of Jaki Leverson" retirement book, 2009; UA030.001.007.00001 (Box 2, Box 7)
    20 years from date of creation.
  - Jaki Leverson memorial program and book, 2010; UA030.001.007.00002 (Box 2, Box 7)
- Annual reports and other accessions, 1960 -- 2018; UA030.002; 7 Folder(s); 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object containing 4 files.; 37.75 Megabytes
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
  This series is not arranged.
  This series contains annual reports, other reports and statistics, Program Guides, photographs, and other files and materials produced by or related to the Tufts Programs Abroad office.
  - Annual Reports, 2005 -- 2017; UA030.002.001; 7 Folder(s) (Box data_value_missing_6d30b4f68e6f95ace67df7784324d3f4, Box 1)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    2005-06 Accession number 2007.041; 2006-07 Accession number 2008.037; 2009-01-15 added accession 2009.060, 2008-09 added 2009-12-14 accession 2010.055 2015-02-17 added accession 2015.047; 2017 added accession UA-2017-006 and UA-2018-005; 2018 added accession UA-2018-025.
  - Annual reports, 2017 -- 2018; UA030; 1 Digital Object(s); 37.75 Megabytes
    Closed 20 years from date of creation.
    This file contains the 2017-2018 annual report and appendices, and reports from Resident Directors of individual programs.
  - Reports and Statistics, 1982 -- 1998; UA030-002 (Box data_value_missing_9b9ab7b011f53adeb75397367bf42b51, Box 1)
    75 years from date of creation.
  - Files and photographs, 1985 -- 1990; UA030-003 (Box data_value_missing_0d381823e2d05da878d7d8efc70573e7, Box 2)
  - Programs Abroad Guides, 1960 -- 2015; UA030-006 (Box data_value_missing_6d83bccf6ad7cf85d0fee318f5a18cdc, Box 3)